RANDOLPH ROY

Software Developer | Technical Project Manager | Creative Manager

\sim	randolphroy@me.com
	305.975.6607
in	linkedin.com/in/randolphroy
C	https://github.com/randolphroy

PROFILE

Web Development and Creative Manager with 15+years of developing and driving positive customer experience interactions. Focused on delivering business value through a customer-focused approach that drives brand loyalty and retention. Service-oriented leader, committed to building high-performing teams and developing top talent to deliver results.

STRENGTHS | ATTRIBUTES |

Web Development • Project Management • Strategic Planning | Development • Leadership • Training & Development • Relationship Building • Business Operations • Creative Direction • Process Improvement

EXPERIENCE

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS / CREATIVE DIRECTOR

TECHTRA GRAPHICS - 2019 - Present

- · Lead all aspects of business operations and creative development for company.
- . Managed team of 30 sales, creative, production, finishing, & instillation associates.
- Designed and implemented company marketing strategy.
- Developed and maintained customer and vendor relationships and promote customer loyalty by ensuring the completion of high-quality deliverables in timely fashion.
- Championed projects in multiple major cities and secured partnerships with #3 supermarket brand and countries National Bank, driving revenue \$100K+ per year.

CUSTOMER SERVICE MANAGER

ORIGIN PC | CORSAIR - 2016 - 2019

- Led multiple departments through acquisition of Origin PC by Corsair, finalized in 2019.
- · Scraped and organized data relating to FreshDesk CRM, volume and flow of inbound calls, critical issues, and repairs.
- Oversaw team of 20 employees across 3 departments-Technical Support, Sales, and Computer Repair.
- Increased company satisfaction from 8.1 to 9.35/10 in less than a year.
- Analyzed data from company's Momentum Telecom report and implemented changes to improve workforce schedule and reduce negative customer experience.
- Resolved critical issues by directly engaging customers to assure satisfaction, brand loyalty, and retention.
- Automated operational processes to improve response rate and drive KPI's, created reports for company executives, and managed team member accounts, utilizing FreshDesk CRM.

DIRECTOR OF OPERATIONS / CREATIVE DIRECTOR

PRINT GIANTS (Co-Owner) - 2009 - 2016

- Developed and maintained customer and vendor relationships and promoted customer loyalty by assuring provision of high-quality deliverables in a timely manner.
- Led expansion of company through development of website for increased visibility and the addition of the large format printing department from concept, strategy to research and purchase of proper printing equipment.
- · Designed and coordinated implementation of company's marketing strategy.
- · Managed office operations including human resources needs and processes.
- · Oversaw the customer service and handled all critical issues and escalations.
- Project Manager for NIKE Launch of LEBRON JAMES 2013 campaign.
- Project Manager for DWYANE WADE New Orleans All Star Game campaign 2013.
- Structured partnership with CABANA Miami Swim Show, bringing yearly revenues of \$35k \$50k.

RANDOLPH ROY

Software Developer | Technical Project Manager | Creative Manager

\bowtie	randolphroy@me.com
	305.975.6607
in	linkedin.com/in/randolphroy
0	https://github.com/randolphroy

EXPERIENCE

CO-OPERATIONS MANAGER / ASSOCIATE CREATIVE DIRECTOR

JPEG GRAPHICS (Co-Owner) - 2002 - 2008

- · Oversaw timely production and delivery of services and products.
- Spearheaded establishment of Atlanta office, building branch from the ground up into a thriving operation with \$1M in gross revenue within two
 years.
- Developed and implemented marketing strategy for Atlanta Office resulting in an increase in clientele and a 200% increase in sales within the first two years.
- Recruited, hired, and trained staff in diverse areas including sales, accounts receivable and payable, and customer service.

TECHNICAL SUPPORT MANAGER

ALIENWARE - 2000 - 2002

- Promoted from Technical Support Associate to Technical Support Manager.
- Worked directly with customer to address needs and solve technical issues.
- Directly oversaw the Critical Issue Team and managed problems and resolutions for high-value clients.
- Oversaw a team of 10 technical support associates, reporting data on call stats to COO.

EDUCATION + CREDENTIALS

Full Stack Web Development Ironhack Technical Bootcamp - 2022

AA, Computer Science Miami Dade College - 1997

SKILLS

TECHNOLOGICAL LANGUAGES & COMPETENCIES

JavaScript (ES6) • React.js • MongoDB/Mongoose • Express.js • Node.js • Git/GitHub • HTML| CSS (Bootstrap/Tailwind) • CompTIA+ • CompTIA Project+ • CIW Site Developer

SOFT SKILLS

Written & Verbal Communication • Customer Experience & Satisfaction • Creative Problem Solving • Conflict resolution • Teamwork • Team Management

LANGUAGES

English • French • Haitian Creole • Spanish (proficient)